KOLD Channel 13 September 11, 2001 Collection, 2001 September 15-2001 December 8
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
KOLD Channel 13 September 11, 2001 Collection, 2001 September 15-2001 December 8
MS 374
KOLD (Television station: Tucson, Ariz.)
This collection documents Tucsonans thoughts and reflections following the attacks of September 11, 2001. As an introduction, KOLD interviewed Dr. Paul Beezley of the University of Arizona History Department. He compared the events to the Civil War and the Battle of Antietam, the bloodiest day in U.S. history. The difference that was drawn between the two events is that the social history of the Civil War is preserved in correspondence from that period. Following the events of September 11, however, correspondence was via email and therefore not preserved. Recognizing this, KOLD sent out a request to viewers asking them to submit their thoughts to KOLD for historical preservation at the University of Arizona Special Collections. Four submissions were selected and read on the air by the authors during subsequent news broadcasts. All submissions are included in this collection.
.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Organization
This collection is organized into seven series.
Within each series, items are arranged alphabetically by the authors' last name.
Series I: Emails, November 1, 2001 to December 8, 2001
Series II: Essays, September 15, 2001 to November 26, 2001
Series III: Letters, November 5, 2001 to December 2, 2001
Series IV: Musical Compact Disc, no date
Series V: Poems, September 24, 2001 to December 6, 2001
Series VI: Scripts of news broadcasts including the interview with Dr. Beezley and authors reading selected reflections, November 1, 2001 to November 29, 2001
Series VII: Video of KOLD News 13 broadcast, November 1, 2001
Access Terms
Beezley, Paul.
September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Personal narratives.
United States -- History -- 21st century.
New York (N.Y.) -- History.
Container List
- Series 1: Emails, November 1, 2001 to December 8, 2001
  - Auby, Aimee (Author), November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barnes, Horace (Author), November 4, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clement, C.B. (Author), November 30, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fong, Patty (Author), November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hacker, Tom (Author), November 24, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hawkins, Dan (Author), December 4, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Marshall, Dean (Author), December 8, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vine, Rochelle (Author), November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 2: Essays, September 15, 2001 to November 26, 2001
  - Andrews, Vanessa (Author), The United States Of America, November 26, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arrington, George (Author), Osama Bin Laden's Folley, October 28, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bullock, James Randolph (Author), My September 11th, November 4, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clifton, Chuck (Author), Terrorists Do Not Determine My Day, September 15, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Flock, Diane (Author), What I was Thinking at the Time of the 9-11 Attacks on America, November 10, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hoffman, Stephen (Author), Justice For All?, November 3, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Howell, Linda (Author), Untitled, October 3, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Love, Rebecca (Author), Untitled, November 30, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - McNurland, Stuart (Author), A Millennium Fairy Tale, No date. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Schunke, Dale W. (Author), 186,000 Miles per Second, November 22, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Skopp, Pat (Author), Untitled, November 24, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Tuuri, Elizabeth (Author), Message to America,November 7, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series 3: Letters, November 5, 2001 to December 2, 2001
  - Bradley, Betty J. (Author), November 29, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hinds, William M. (Author), December 2, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Reno, Marilyn (Author), November 27, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Siefers, Jill R. (Author), No date. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wise, Bonnie (Author), November 5, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series 4: Musical Compact Disc, No date
  - Tippins, Louis (Author), No date. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series 5: Poems, September 24, 2001 to December 6, 2001
  - Apel, Harry James (Author), I'm an American, Red, White and Blue, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Barrasso, Brennen (Author), Sad September, No date. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Camacho, Hector (Author), Heavens Lost, October 31, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Carranza, Andrew (Author), September 11, 2001, No date. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Champion, Corey (Author), Let Freedom Ring, November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Endsret, Jeff (Author), The Hero's Poem, November 23, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fox-Perez, Christin (Author), Pain, September 24, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gambil, Pat (Author), Song of America, November 24, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gardner, Diana (Author), The Night Before and After Ground Zero, November 22, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Gilmore, Tresma (Author), United We Stand, November 30, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gordon, Emily (Author), Untitled, No date. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hafer, Aurelia (Author), Freedom is Not Free & The Mark of the Brave, November 16, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Hansen, Pete Benjamin (Author), Prayers Amiss, November 9, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Harding, Audra (Author), Lest We Forget, December 6, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Jordan, David (Author), Untitled, No date. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Manuel, Shannon (Author), Untitled, December 6, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Martinez, Jason (Author), A Day of Great Infamy, No date. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Mathero, Dusty (Author), Untitled, No date. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Neider, Sr. Janet M. (Author), Let Freedom Ring, November 24, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Pederson, Alex (Author), Courage, No date. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Rascon, Genevieve (Author), Untitled, December 6, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Shipley, Cassandra (Author), September 11, 2001, No date. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - T., Louis (Author), Untitled, No date. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Villegas, Maritza, B., United We Stand, December 6, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - (No Author), A Sad Dark Day: September 11, 2001, November 16, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Series 6: Scripts of news broadcasts including the interview with Dr. Beezley and authors reading selected reflections, November 1, 2001 to November 29, 2001
  - Interview with Dr. Paul Beezley, November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Slavin, Pamela (Author), Untitled Poem, November 2, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Smith, Maria (Author), September 11 Essay, November 5, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Interview with U of A Special Collections Archivists, November 29, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Valencic, Sheryal (Author), Email, November 24, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Wright, Barbara (Author), Email, November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Series 7: Video of KOLD News 13 broadcast, November 1, 2001
  - KOLD News 13 (Author), Viewers Respond to Terrorist Attacks, November 1, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 58)